<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>All-maker internet space Blog</title>
        <link>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog</link>
        <description>All-maker internet space Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Life is an MVP]]></title>
            <link>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/mvp</link>
            <guid>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/mvp</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Whatever can be, will be.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Whatever can be, will be.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Technical Writing</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Redefining technical writing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/redefining-technical-writing</link>
            <guid>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/redefining-technical-writing</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[You may think of a technical writer as the person who produces documentation. But the role has changed. It now sits at the center of design thinking, context protocols, content strategy, user journeys, AI-augmented authoring, automated workflows, docs as a product, and communication between humans and machines.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You may think of a technical writer as the person who produces documentation. But the role has changed. It now sits at the center of design thinking, context protocols, content strategy, user journeys, AI-augmented authoring, automated workflows, docs as a product, and communication between humans and machines.</p>
<p>If you still treat technical writing as a support function, you will miss where product value now lives.</p>
<p>Language is no longer a layer on top of software. It shapes how software behaves. In AI-native systems, language is part of the system.</p>
<p>You do not need a better writer. You need someone who designs how knowledge flows across your organization and your product.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="start-with-the-system-not-the-document">Start with the system, not the document<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/redefining-technical-writing#start-with-the-system-not-the-document" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Start with the system, not the document" title="Direct link to Start with the system, not the document" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>You do not scale documentation by writing more pages. You scale it by designing the system that produces, structures, and distributes knowledge.</p>
<p>Modern products are complex. They include APIs, integrations, agents, workflows, and AI features. Users do not interact with a single screen. They move across surfaces, contexts, and states. Machines also consume your content. LLMs read it. Agents act on it.</p>
<p>If you do not design your knowledge architecture, it will fragment.</p>
<p><strong>The modern technical writer must design the system behind the content, not just the content itself.</strong>
You shift from writing documents to designing knowledge infrastructure.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="apply-design-thinking-to-knowledge">Apply design thinking to knowledge<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/redefining-technical-writing#apply-design-thinking-to-knowledge" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Apply design thinking to knowledge" title="Direct link to Apply design thinking to knowledge" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>You already apply design thinking to product features. You must apply the same rigor to knowledge.</p>
<p>Start with user problems. Map moments of confusion. Identify where users drop off. Treat documentation as part of the user journey, not as an afterthought.</p>
<p>When you design knowledge around real tasks, you reduce support tickets, shorten onboarding time, and improve activation.</p>
<p>You stop asking, "What should we document?" and start asking, "Where does the user lose clarity?"
You design knowledge around user friction, not around product releases.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="define-context-protocols-for-humans-and-machines">Define context protocols for humans and machines<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/redefining-technical-writing#define-context-protocols-for-humans-and-machines" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Define context protocols for humans and machines" title="Direct link to Define context protocols for humans and machines" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>AI systems depend on context. If your knowledge lacks structure, your AI will drift.</p>
<p>You must define canonical terms, consistent definitions, structured formats, and reusable components. You must ensure that product logic translates clearly into machine-readable form.</p>
<p>When you do this work well, you reduce hallucination risk, improve output consistency, and protect user trust.</p>
<p><strong>Context does not emerge by accident. You must design it.</strong>
You own the rules that shape how humans and machines interpret your product.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="build-a-content-strategy-that-scales">Build a content strategy that scales<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/redefining-technical-writing#build-a-content-strategy-that-scales" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Build a content strategy that scales" title="Direct link to Build a content strategy that scales" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>Content strategy no longer means planning blog posts or release notes. It means deciding how information becomes reusable, structured, and maintainable.</p>
<p>You must decide:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">What becomes structured data.</li>
<li class="">What becomes reusable components.</li>
<li class="">What becomes API-readable.</li>
<li class="">What should not exist at all.</li>
</ul>
<p>When you treat content as a system, you reduce redundancy and increase speed. Engineers, support teams, and AI systems can rely on the same source of truth.</p>
<p><strong>Scale does not come from writing faster. It comes from structuring better.</strong>
You design content to behave like infrastructure, not like static text.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="design-user-journeys-across-surfaces">Design user journeys across surfaces<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/redefining-technical-writing#design-user-journeys-across-surfaces" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Design user journeys across surfaces" title="Direct link to Design user journeys across surfaces" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>Users do not distinguish between UI, docs, and support. They experience a single journey.</p>
<p>You must map how users move from product interface to documentation, from documentation to AI assistance, and from AI to support. You must design recovery paths when something fails.</p>
<p>Clear transitions increase confidence. Confidence drives adoption.</p>
<p><strong>Documentation is part of your product experience, whether you admit it or not.</strong>
You design continuity across every moment where understanding can break.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="build-ai-augmented-authoring-flows">Build AI-augmented authoring flows<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/redefining-technical-writing#build-ai-augmented-authoring-flows" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Build AI-augmented authoring flows" title="Direct link to Build AI-augmented authoring flows" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>You cannot scale knowledge with manual effort alone. You must design how AI supports content creation.</p>
<p>Create structured templates. Build prompt libraries. Automate review processes. Use AI for consistency checks, terminology validation, and structural alignment.</p>
<p>When you design authoring flows intentionally, you improve speed and quality at the same time.</p>
<p><strong>AI should not replace writers. It should extend them.</strong>
You design the system that makes humans and AI collaborate effectively.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="automate-content-workflows">Automate content workflows<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/redefining-technical-writing#automate-content-workflows" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Automate content workflows" title="Direct link to Automate content workflows" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>If your documentation process relies on manual updates, you will fall behind.</p>
<p>You must integrate version control, structured content models, and automated publishing pipelines. Connect documentation to product changes. Treat knowledge like code, with review processes, traceability, and iteration.</p>
<p>Automation reduces errors and prevents knowledge decay.</p>
<p><strong>Operational discipline applies to content just as much as it applies to engineering.</strong>
You apply DevOps thinking to knowledge management.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="treat-docs-as-a-product">Treat docs as a product<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/redefining-technical-writing#treat-docs-as-a-product" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Treat docs as a product" title="Direct link to Treat docs as a product" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>Documentation influences onboarding, activation, retention, and developer experience. You must treat it like a product.</p>
<p>Define metrics. Analyze usage patterns. Test changes. Prioritize improvements. Maintain a roadmap.</p>
<p>When you invest in documentation strategically, you reduce support costs and increase user success.</p>
<p><strong>Docs do not support the product. Docs are part of the product.</strong>
You manage documentation with the same rigor as any customer-facing feature.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="navigate-communication-between-humans-and-machines">Navigate communication between humans and machines<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/redefining-technical-writing#navigate-communication-between-humans-and-machines" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Navigate communication between humans and machines" title="Direct link to Navigate communication between humans and machines" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>In AI-enabled systems, language becomes executable. Prompts shape behavior. Output shapes trust.</p>
<p>You must translate product logic into instructions machines can interpret. You must translate machine output into explanations humans can understand. You must design transparency, disclaimers, and recovery paths.</p>
<p>If you ignore this layer, risk increases. Confusion spreads. Trust erodes.</p>
<p><strong>Someone must own the interface between human intention and machine behavior.</strong>
You design how intelligence expresses itself through language.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="redefine-the-role">Redefine the role<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/redefining-technical-writing#redefine-the-role" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Redefine the role" title="Direct link to Redefine the role" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>The traditional title "technical writer" no longer captures the scope of this work.</p>
<p>You now design knowledge systems, context architecture, AI interaction patterns, workflow automation, and cross-surface user journeys. You influence product clarity, AI reliability, operational efficiency, and user trust.</p>
<p>Language shapes how your system thinks. Structure shapes how it scales.</p>
<p><strong>You do not just write documentation.</strong>
You design how understanding works inside your product and your organization.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alien tech writer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/alien</link>
            <guid>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/alien</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I've always pondered our definition of human intelligence. Civilization even. A definition that I like is — our ability to manipulate our environment.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I've always pondered our definition of human intelligence. Civilization even. A definition that I like is — our ability to manipulate our environment.</p>
<p>Lately, I've been thinking about the necessity of it all. After all, we did invent all of this marvel out of necessity for better tooling, food production, shelter, and so on.</p>
<p>The way we perceive the world and are able to shape it naturally has made us make use of our biggest advantage — the mind.</p>
<p>But we know of different beings with better senses, capabilities, and even immortality. The way we perceive the world, even through sophisticated technology, might still fall short of what a mantis shrimp is able to perceive.</p>
<p>Now imagine a thought experiment. A vastly superior biological extraterrestrial being visits Earth. Not a civilization with better ships or weapons — a being whose very biology allows it to perceive the universe in its entirety. All the dimensions we theorize about, all the quantum phenomena we struggle to measure, all the forces and fields we can only detect through instruments built over centuries of incremental progress. To this being, the universe isn't a mystery to be solved. It's just... visible.</p>
<p>They look at us and see completely limited beings. Creatures harvesting energy from the elements, building tooling solutions to make up for their lack of vision and understanding. Translating the world into symbols and equations because they cannot simply <em>see</em> it.</p>
<p>And yet — they might be impressed. Because given that the only real tool at our disposal is the brain, we've gotten remarkably far.</p>
<p>A human rebuttal, then. In a way, that is even better. If you are a being whose understanding depends entirely on a biological gift — some innate sensory apparatus you were born with — and you lose it, you are left in the dark. Unable to navigate, perhaps unable to sustain yourself at all.</p>
<p>But humans figure it out. We always have. We lack the hardware, so we build it. We can't perceive ultraviolet light, so we invent sensors that can. We can't fly, so we engineer flight. We don't have the answer, so we design a process to find it.</p>
<p>It's better to have a thinking process than a specialized capability. Capabilities can fail. Thinking adapts.</p>
<p>This is how I feel as a tech writer. I don't always have the perfect tools. But I figure it out.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Opinion</category>
            <category>Technical Writing</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech and art]]></title>
            <link>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/tech-art</link>
            <guid>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/tech-art</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Tech keeps you capable. Art keeps you sane.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tech keeps you capable. Art keeps you sane.</p>
<p>That's the whole thesis. I could stop here. But I already wrote the title, so.</p>
<p>Technology — the tools, the systems, the automations — makes you self-reliant. You can fix your own plumbing because YouTube exists. You can build a website because frameworks exist. You can troubleshoot your car, set up a home network, file your taxes, and never ask another human being for help.</p>
<p>That's powerful. That's independence.</p>
<p>But it's also just capability. It's infrastructure. It keeps the machine running. It doesn't tell you <em>why</em> the machine should run in the first place.</p>
<p>That's where art comes in.</p>
<p>And I'm using "art" loosely. I don't mean you need to paint like Monet or write like Hemingway. I mean the guitar and a beer in the evening when the world is quiet. That leather EDC wallet you've stitched crookedly by hand. The weird poem on your phone that no one will ever read or that welding project that turned into a sculpture.</p>
<p>The stuff with no sprint ticket. No deadline. No stakeholder.</p>
<p>Tech solves problems. Art reminds you that not everything is a problem to be solved. Some things just exist to be felt, made, and left alone.</p>
<p>I write docs all day. I structure knowledge, design user journeys, and think in headings and bullet points. It's satisfying in the way that organizing a toolbox is satisfying — everything in its place, everything serving a function.</p>
<p>But when I pick up a guitar, or lose an hour learning how to bevel leather edges — nothing is in its place. There's no information architecture. There's no user. There's just me and the thing I'm making, and it's never perfect. But, boy, oh boy, is it satisfying.</p>
<p>Keeps me sane.</p>
<p>If everything is optimized, structured, and efficient — great. You've built a really well-structured machine.</p>
<p>But machines don't need meaning. You do.</p>
<p>Use the tech. Keeps you capable.
Feed the art. It keeps you human.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Opinion</category>
            <category>Lifestyle</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arguing with a robot]]></title>
            <link>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/argue-with-robot</link>
            <guid>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/argue-with-robot</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I tried this insert product so you don't have to.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I tried this <em>insert product</em> so you don't have to.</p>
<p>There's a myriad of AI tool reviews out there. Kind of reminds me of the whole microservices hype. I swear, for about two years this buzzword was in every single meeting I attended. Now it's "AI-powered" everything. AI-powered toaster. AI-powered calendar. AI-powered AI.</p>
<p>So what's the point in writing this?</p>
<p>I just use them. I switch between the tools and models. Find what works, get the job done, and move on. A lot of trial and error. No hype. No manifestos. Just a tech writer trying to ship docs faster without losing his mind.</p>
<p>If you haven't already, check out <a class="" href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/cheap-tools">Use cheap tools until they break</a> — it sets up the mindset for everything below. The short version: master the craft first, then upgrade your tools. AI is the latest upgrade.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="enter-the-robots">Enter the robots<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/argue-with-robot#enter-the-robots" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Enter the robots" title="Direct link to Enter the robots" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>LLMs are the newest tools in the belt. And for now, they're cheap. Accessible. Everywhere.</p>
<p>The mistake I see people make is treating them like either a silver bullet or a threat. They're neither. They're tools. And like all tools, they're only as good as the person using them.</p>
<p>Here's how I actually use them.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="the-second-opinion">The second opinion<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/argue-with-robot#the-second-opinion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The second opinion" title="Direct link to The second opinion" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>I give different models or agents different personas and ask them to critique each other. Not because I think AI knows better than me — but because it's faster than waiting three days for a peer review just to catch a typo and a broken link.</p>
<p>I'll draft something in Claude, then ask Gemini to poke holes in it. Or I'll set up two agents — one playing the role of a skeptical developer, the other a first-time user — and have them both review the same doc. You'd be surprised what falls out.</p>
<p>This isn't about replacing human review. It's about showing up to the human review with fewer obvious issues.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="the-pipeline-nobody-built">The pipeline nobody built<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/argue-with-robot#the-pipeline-nobody-built" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The pipeline nobody built" title="Direct link to The pipeline nobody built" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>Here's a real example. I inherited a codebase where the developers never wrote explicit API documentation. No OpenAPI spec. Nothing. The endpoints existed in the code, scattered across files, undocumented.</p>
<p>So I set up multiple LLM agents — different models, different instructions — and had them analyze the code, generate OpenAPI specs, and then argue with each other about whether the specs were accurate. One agent generates. Another validates. A third tries to break it.</p>
<p>The result isn't perfect. But it's a starting point that would have taken weeks to produce manually. And now there's a single source of truth where there was none.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="instruction-files-and-prompt-libraries">Instruction files and prompt libraries<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/argue-with-robot#instruction-files-and-prompt-libraries" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Instruction files and prompt libraries" title="Direct link to Instruction files and prompt libraries" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>Keep markdown files with instructions per use case. I have different ones for different tasks — reviewing for plain language, checking structural consistency, generating code samples, and so on. When you reuse the same prompt across projects, it becomes a tool in itself. Sharpen it over time.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="modes-of-working-with-ai">Modes of working with AI<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/argue-with-robot#modes-of-working-with-ai" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Modes of working with AI" title="Direct link to Modes of working with AI" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>Not all AI-augmented work looks the same. The way I see it, there are a few distinct modes, and knowing when to use which one matters more than which model you pick.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="chat--the-rubber-duck">Chat — the rubber duck<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/argue-with-robot#chat--the-rubber-duck" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Chat — the rubber duck" title="Direct link to Chat — the rubber duck" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>Open a browser tab. Talk to it like a colleague. Ask it to explain a codebase you just inherited. Bounce an outline off it. Get a second opinion on your content architecture before you spend two days building it.</p>
<p>Best for: exploration, understanding, brainstorming.</p>
<p>Tools: Claude, ChatGPT, Gemini — browser-based, conversational.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="inline-assist--the-co-pilot">Inline assist — the co-pilot<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/argue-with-robot#inline-assist--the-co-pilot" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Inline assist — the co-pilot" title="Direct link to Inline assist — the co-pilot" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>This is your IDE whispering suggestions as you type. Tab completion, reformatting, fixing broken links, repetitive edits across 40 files. It's not creative work — it's grunt work you shouldn't be doing manually.</p>
<p>Best for: repetitive tasks, pattern-based edits, formatting.</p>
<p>Tools: GitHub Copilot, Cursor, Cody, any IDE-integrated assistant.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="drafting--the-ghostwriter">Drafting — the ghostwriter<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/argue-with-robot#drafting--the-ghostwriter" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Drafting — the ghostwriter" title="Direct link to Drafting — the ghostwriter" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>You provide the context, the constraints, the style guide. The AI generates a first draft. You refine. This works surprisingly well for things like release notes, API reference descriptions, and structured content where the format is predictable.</p>
<p>Best for: first drafts, boilerplate, structured content.</p>
<p>One rule: if the output is good, use it. Don't feel obligated to rewrite a perfectly fine doc just because AI wrote it.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="automation--the-assembly-line">Automation — the assembly line<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/argue-with-robot#automation--the-assembly-line" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Automation — the assembly line" title="Direct link to Automation — the assembly line" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>This is where it gets interesting. CI/CD integration. Style linting. Automated spec generation. Agents that run in the background and flag issues before you even open the file. This mode requires setup, but once it's running, it scales in a way that manual work never will.</p>
<p>Best for: validation, spec generation, continuous quality checks.</p>
<p>Tools: Claude Code, OpenHands, custom scripts, MCP servers, whatever gets the job done.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="pick-the-model-not-the-brand">Pick the model, not the brand<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/argue-with-robot#pick-the-model-not-the-brand" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Pick the model, not the brand" title="Direct link to Pick the model, not the brand" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>Different models are better at different things. As of right now, here's how I think about it:</p>
<ul>
<li class=""><strong>Claude</strong> — strong at long-form writing, structured content, and following detailed instructions. My go-to for doc work.</li>
<li class=""><strong>GPT</strong> — solid generalist. Good at code generation and quick answers. The ecosystem is massive.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Gemini</strong> — great context window. Useful when you need to feed it an entire codebase or a 200-page spec and ask questions.</li>
</ul>
<p>This changes every few months. Don't marry a model. Date all of them.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="the-actual-point">The actual point<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/argue-with-robot#the-actual-point" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The actual point" title="Direct link to The actual point" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>None of this matters if you don't have the fundamentals. AI won't save you if you don't understand your users, can't structure content, or don't know what simplified technical English is.</p>
<p>The tools amplify what you already have. If what you have is solid craft — structured authoring, user-centered thinking, domain knowledge, a willingness to figure it out — then AI makes you faster, broader, and harder to replace.</p>
<p>If what you have is vibes and a ChatGPT subscription, well. The cheap tool is going to break real fast.</p>
<p>Use whatever is at your disposal to get the product out. Then get better. Then get faster. Then help someone else do the same.</p>
<p>That's the job.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Technical Writing</category>
            <category>AI</category>
            <category>Tools</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Use cheap tools until they break]]></title>
            <link>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/cheap-tools</link>
            <guid>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/cheap-tools</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Adam Savage once said that as a hobbyist, you should buy the cheapest tools you can find and use them until they break. When they break — and they will — you'll know two things: you're serious about the craft, and you now know exactly what you need. Then you buy the best tools you can afford.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Adam Savage once said that as a hobbyist, you should buy the cheapest tools you can find and use them until they break. When they break — and they will — you'll know two things: you're serious about the craft, and you now know exactly what you need. Then you buy the best tools you can afford.</p>
<p>This translates beautifully to technical writing.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="start-with-what-gets-the-docs-out-the-door">Start with what gets the docs out the door<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/cheap-tools#start-with-what-gets-the-docs-out-the-door" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Start with what gets the docs out the door" title="Direct link to Start with what gets the docs out the door" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>If you're early in your career, or switching to docs-as-code, or just getting started with structured authoring — use whatever ships the docs. Paligo. FrameMaker. Zendesk. Confluence. A CCMS that lets you publish topics and structure content? Great. IntelliJ's visual Git interface so you don't have to memorize CLI commands on day one? Totally fine. I love that thing.</p>
<p>The point is: don't let tooling anxiety stop you from shipping.</p>
<p>The skills matter more than the stack. Structured authoring, simplified technical English, user experience, content architecture — these don't change because you switched from Confluence to a static site generator. The fundamentals are the fundamentals. Focus on the process, the knowledge, and the writing.</p>
<p>Learn how to interview a developer. Learn how to break down a feature into tasks a reader can actually follow. Learn how to say the same thing in half the words. None of that requires a terminal.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="when-the-cheap-tool-breaks">When the cheap tool breaks<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/cheap-tools#when-the-cheap-tool-breaks" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to When the cheap tool breaks" title="Direct link to When the cheap tool breaks" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>You'll know when it happens.</p>
<p>The GUI can't handle your reuse model. The CMS chokes on your branching strategy. You need automation that doesn't exist yet. You're copy-pasting the same update across 40 files and thinking there has to be a better way.</p>
<p>There is. And you're ready for it — because you've hit the wall.</p>
<p>That's when you go all in. CLI. Scripting. Pipelines. You start single-sourcing your OpenAPI specs straight from the source code. You automate generation of the sneak preview and the release notes. You add linters and style guides that run in CI. You set up an AI assistant that catches issues before you even open the file.</p>
<p>And here's the thing. By this point? You're not guessing. You're not automating for the sake of automating. You know exactly which part of the workflow is broken because you lived in it. You used the cheap tools. You developed the essential skills. Now you're investing your time where it actually matters.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="afford-doesnt-mean-money">"Afford" doesn't mean money<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/cheap-tools#afford-doesnt-mean-money" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to &quot;Afford&quot; doesn't mean money" title="Direct link to &quot;Afford&quot; doesn't mean money" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>In this context, "the best tools you can afford" means time.</p>
<p>If you can invest in Python and version control from day one, do it. But if you're unsure about the career, hard-pressed for time, or just overwhelmed — resolve your merge conflicts visually and move on. No shame.</p>
<p>The tools don't make the writer. The writer makes the tools worth using.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="see-also">See also<a href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/cheap-tools#see-also" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to See also" title="Direct link to See also" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li class=""><a class="" href="https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/argue-with-robot">Arguing with a robot</a></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Technical Writing</category>
            <category>Tools</category>
            <category>Career</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech bro VS caveman]]></title>
            <link>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/tech-bro</link>
            <guid>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/tech-bro</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Something weird is happening in tech.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Something weird is happening in tech.</p>
<p>The people who build the apps, configure the notifications, and automate everything they can — are the same people turning it all off.</p>
<p>I keep seeing it. Senior devs ditching smartphones for dumbphones. DevOps engineers building birdhouses on weekends. The person who automated their entire CI/CD pipeline now drives a manual car with no navigation and calls it "meditation."</p>
<p>And honestly? I get it.</p>
<p>Think about your average Tuesday. You wake up and there are already 14 notifications. Slack. Email. That one app reminding you to drink water as if you're a newly arrived alien. You manage passwords with a password manager that also needs a password. You juggle subscriptions, insurances, logins, two-factor codes, and a calendar that looks like a Tetris board designed by someone who hates you.</p>
<p>Then you go to work.</p>
<p>Stakeholder meetings. Sprint planning. Making sense out of chaos so someone else can ship a feature that adds more notifications to the pile. You write structured content, optimize headings, and think about user journeys so hard your own journey becomes a blur.</p>
<p>At some point, something gives.</p>
<p>For me, it's the sauna. No phone. No screen. No noise. Just heat, steam, and the kind of silence that makes your ears ring because you forgot what silence actually sounds like.</p>
<p>Or cooking. Something slow and intentionally messy, where the worst-case scenario is you oversalt the soup.</p>
<p>Or fixing things around the house. A leaky faucet doesn't need a Jira ticket. You just grab the wrench, figure it out, and move on. No PR review required.</p>
<p>Or — and this is the one that really resets the brain — sitting on the floor with my four-year-old and doing whatever I'm told. Build this tower. No, not like that. Now knock it down. Again.</p>
<p>No strategy. No optimization. No purpose beyond the moment.</p>
<p>There's no standup for playing with blocks.</p>
<p>He doesn't have a system. He doesn't batch his tasks or timebox his play. He just does the thing in front of him, fully, and moves on. Somewhere between learning to crawl and learning to code, we forgot how to do that.</p>
<p>Our brains were built for maybe 50 decisions a day. Hunt or gather. Sleep or stay alert. Now we make 50 decisions before breakfast — most of them about cookies, and not the edible kind.</p>
<p>No wonder the techiest people alive are buying flip phones and building cabins.</p>
<p>The hardware can't keep up with the software update.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Opinion</category>
            <category>Lifestyle</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pizza]]></title>
            <link>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/pizza</link>
            <guid>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/pizza</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[What are the most important aspects of being a technical writer?]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What are the most important aspects of being a technical writer?</p>
<p>I used to have a ready answer to this question. But now, I look at it a bit differently and an anecdote comes to mind.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>Fresh out of uni, I worked as a translator. I got a gig to translate, subtitle, and dub an instructional video on how to make pizza. It was for a pizza academy created by a well-known pizza maker.</p>
<p>Doing research, I asked him somewhat bluntly: "Is making the dough the most important part?" He answered: "Every step is important."</p>
<p>My cooking inexperience and the lack of domain knowledge led me to assume pizza making was simple. I identified the part that was hard for <em>me</em> to be the only one that mattered. I disregarded the sauce, the arrangement, and the baking method.</p>
<p>With docs, our job is to educate. Not only through the end product, but through&nbsp;the process as well. Not everybody knows the amount of research and analysis that precedes the doc work. Or the stakeholder and SME management, structuring, content strategy, writing and reviewing processes, plain language, user journeys. Or the pains of single-sourcing, automation, multi-channel publishing, localization, accessibility, and so on.&nbsp;</p>
<p>And of course, with all of that comes the inescapable truth of always having to keep up with your product's development, continuously expand your&nbsp;domain knowledge, and closely participate in testing and design.</p>
<p>If you can handle all of that, manage to pass it along to your peers and community, and inspire others to get better, always, one step&nbsp;at a time - you start to confidently step into the role of a tech writer.</p>
<p>And the pizza gets better.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[About this blog]]></title>
            <link>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/intro</link>
            <guid>https://www.all-maker.com/pr-preview/pr-13/blog/intro</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Sometimes, you just need to write it down.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Sometimes, you just need to write it down.</em></p>
<p>Hello everybody! Welcome, welcome.</p>
<p>At the time of posting this, my plan for this blog is not to write instructional content as I would at a corporation. Rather, I want to offer my experience about what I've done so far and how I found it easier to do. But maybe most of all, I want to reinforce my discipline, planning, and day-to-day.</p>
<p>One of the reasons behind this is from 2019 when I learned how to create a website for a portfolio from a YouTube video. I managed to put my CV online in 2 hours. It's still <a href="https://strahinjamilosevic.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">online</a>.</p>
<p>It wasn't optimal for authoring experience, pipeline, SEO, and especially the content. But it was fast, free, looked okay and got the job done.</p>
<p>So, I want to try and tailor the content to show how I do things in a way optimized for <em>me</em>. Maybe you find it helpful. Maybe it sparks something within you and inspires you to do it better.</p>
<p>You know what they say: If you want something done quickly, post an incorrect fact online. People will flock to correct you.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>